Spanish Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Spanish Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 24
Yale University Arts Library
16.25
39 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Spanish paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work. The individual artist portion is preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Spanish paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Painting, Spanish; Photographs; Reproductions
- Anonymous
  Scope and Contents
  Beginning of file includes several folders of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Dates not known., 2 (Box 1)
    - X Century., 2 (Box 1)
  - XI Century., 3 (Box 1)
  - XII Century., 88 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 39 (Box 1)
    - Berlanga., 4 (Box 1)
    - Leon., 5 (Box 1)
    - S. Maria del Mur., 3 (Box 1)
    - Solsona., 6 (Box 1)
    - Tahull., 17 (Box 2)
    - Vich., 15 (Box 2)
  - XIII Century., 21 (Box 2)
  - XIV Century., 21 (Box 2)
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - XV Century., 48 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 23 (Box 3)
    - Barcelona., 11 (Box 3)
    - New York., 8 (Box 3)
    - Tarragona., 6 (Box 3)
  - XVI Century., 21 (Box 3)
  - XVII Century., 18 (Box 3)
  - XVIII Century., 1 (Box 4)
- A (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Artists A., 6 (Box 4)
    - Afonso, Jorge, active 1508-1540., 1 (Box 4)
    - Alvarez, Luis, 1841-1901., 2 (Box 4)
    - Andres Marsal de Sax, active 1394-1405., 1 (Box 4)
    - Arroyo, Eduardo, 1937-., 2 (Box 4)
  - Individual Artists A., 7 (Box 4)
    - Andreu, Mariano, 1888-., 2 (Box 4)
    - Antolinez, Claudio, 1635-1675., 5 (Box 4)
- B (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Artists B., 9 (Box 4)
    - Bassa, Ferrer, -1348., 1 (Box 4)
    - Benabarre, Pedro Garcia de, XV C., 2 (Box 4)
    - Bermejo, Bartolome, active 1490-1495., 1 (Box 4)
    - Berruguete, Pedro, active 1457-1503., 2 (Box 4)
    - Beruete, Aureliano de, 1845-1912., 1 (Box 4)
    - Bores, Francisco, 1898-., 1 (Box 4)
    - Burgos y Mantilla, Francisco, active 1631., 1 (Box 4)
  - Individual Artists B., 21 (Box 4)
    - Bayeu, Francisco, 1734-1795., 5 (Box 4)
    - Bermejo, Bartolome, active 1490-1495., 4 (Box 4)
    - Borrassa, Luis, active 1396-1424., 12 (Box 4)
- C (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Artists C., 12 (Box 4)
    - Calderon, Philip Hermogenes, 1833-1898., 2 (Box 4)
    - Camilo, Francisco, c.1614-1673., 1 (Box 4)
    - Canals, Ricardo, 1876-1931., 1 (Box 4)
    - Carducci, Bartolommeo, 1560-1608., 1 (Box 4)
    - Carducho, Vicente, 1578-1638., 1 (Box 4)
    - Carrion, Juan Francisco, active 1672., 1 (Box 4)
    - Casanova y Estorich, Antonie, 1847-1896., 1 (Box 4)
    - Casas, Ramon, 1866-1932., 1 (Box 4)
    - Castello, Felix, 1602-1656., 1 (Box 4)
    - Clave, Antoni, 1913-., 1 (Box 4)
    - Cuixart, Modesto, 1925-., 1 (Box 4)
  - Individual Artists C., 69 (Box 4)
    - Cano, Alonso, 1601-1667., 14 (Box 4)
    - Carreno de Miranda, Juan, 1614-1685., 4 (Box 4)
    - Castillo, Antonio del, 1616-1668., 5 (Box 4)
    - Caviedes, Hipolito Hidalgo de, XX C., 2 (Box 4)
    - Cerezo, Matteo, 1635-1685., 2 (Box 5)
    - Coello, Alonso Sanchez, 1515-1590., 29 (Box 5)
    - Coello, Claudio, 1630-1693., 11 (Box 5)
    - Collantes, Francisco, 1599-1656., 2 (Box 5)
- D (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Artists D., 7 (Box 5)
    - Diaz, Daniel Vazquez, 1882-., 1 (Box 5)
    - Dolce, Carlo, 1616-1686., 1 (Box 5)
    - Domingo y Marques, Francisco, 1842-1920., 1 (Box 5)
    - Dominguez, Oscar, 1906-1958., 3 (Box 5)
    - Dosal, Francisco, XIX C., 1 (Box 5)
  - Individual Artists D., 94 (Box 5)
    - Dali, Salvador, 1904-1989., 45 (Box 5)
    - Dali, Salvador, 1904-1989., 44 (Box 6)
    - Dalmau, Luis, active 1428-1461., 6 (Box 6)
- E (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Artists E., 6
    - Echave, Balthasar, active 1630., 1 (Box 6)
    - Escalante, Juan Antonio, 1630-1670., 1 (Box 6)
    - Escamilla, Luis Tristan de, c.1586-1624., 1 (Box 6)
    - Escosura, Leon Y., 1840-1901., 1 (Box 6)
    - Espalargucs, Pedro, active 1490., 1
      Also known as Pedro Despallargues.
    - Espinosa, Juan Bautista, c.1585-1640., 1 (Box 6)
- F (Box 6)
  - Individual Artists F., 29 (Box 6)
    - Fernandez, Alejo, c.1470-1543., 2 (Box 6)
    - Fortuny y Carbo, Mariano, 1838-1874., 27 (Box 6)
- G (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Artists G., 5 (Box 6)
    - Gisbert, Antonio, active 1859-1880., 1 (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez, Bartolome, 1564-1627., 1 (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez, Julio, 1876-1942., 1 (Box 6)
    - Gonzales-Velasquez, Antonio, 1723-1793., 1 (Box 6)
    - Grau-Sala, Emilio, 1911-., 1 (Box 6)
  - Individual Artists G., 824 (Box 7)
    - Gallegos, Fernando, 1440-1507., 24 (Box 7)
    - Garcia-Hidalgo, Jose, 1642-1722., 8 (Box 7)
    - Goya, Francisco de, 1746-1828., 377 (Box 7)
      - Drawings., 31 (Box 7)
      - Paintings., 346 (Box 8)
        - Locations not noted., 34
        - Private collections., 17 (Box 8)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 39 (Box 8)
        - Boston., 5 (Box 9)
        - Budapest., 7 (Box 9)
        - Chicago., 14 (Box 9)
        - Cincinnati., 2 (Box 9)
        - Cleveland., 6 (Box 9)
        - Lille., 12 (Box 9)
        - London., 18 (Box 9)
        - Madrid., 84 (Box 9)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 10 (Box 9)
          - Academia de San Fernando., 11 (Box 9)
          - San Antonio de la Florida., 7 (Box 10)
          - Prado., 56 (Box 10)
            - Miscellaneous subjects., 43 (Box 10)
            - Insurrection of May 2, 1808., 3 (Box 10)
            - Maja Desnuda & Vestida., 5 (Box 10)
            - Shooting in Madrid., 8 (Box 10)
        - Munich., 9 (Box 10)
        - New York., 57 (Box 11)
        - Northampton., 2 (Box 11)
        - Paris., 5 (Box 11)
        - San Diego., 3 (Box 11)
        - Toledo., 3 (Box 11)
        - Vienna., 5 (Box 11)
        - Washington, D.C., 21 (Box 12)
        - Worcester, MA., 3 (Box 12)
    - El Greco, 1541-1614., 325 (Box 12)
      - Locations not noted., 21 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 22 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 22 (Box 13)
      - Boston., 5 (Box 13)
      - Chicago., 8 (Box 13)
      - Cincinnati., 2 (Box 13)
      - Cleveland., 9 (Box 13)
      - Edinburgh., 2 (Box 13)
      - Escorial., 7 (Box 13)
      - Glasgow., 2 (Box 13)
      - Illescas., 6 (Box 13)
      - Kansas City., 5 (Box 13)
      - Leningrad., 2 (Box 13)
      - London., 19 (Box 13)
      - Madrid., 26 (Box 14)
      - Minneapolis., 7 (Box 14)
      - Montreal., 3 (Box 14)
      - Munich., 15 (Box 14)
      - New York., 41 (Box 14)
      - Paris., 5 (Box 15)
      - Philadelphia., 3 (Box 15)
      - San Francisco., 12 (Box 15)
      - Toledo, Spain., 31 (Box 15)
      - Toledo, Ohio., 10 (Box 15)
      - Washington, D.C., 30 (Box 15)
      - El Greco, Son of, 1578-1631., 6 (Box 16)
        Also called Jorge Manuel Theotocopuli.
      - El Greco, Workshop of., 7 (Box 16)
    - Gris, Juan, 1887-1927., 86 (Box 16)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 16)
      - Paintings., 82 (Box 16)
      - Locations not noted and private collections., 29 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 24 (Box 16)
      - Bern., 2 (Box 16)
      - Chicago., 4 (Box 16)
      - New York., 12 (Box 17)
      - Otterlo., 6 (Box 17)
      - Pittsburgh., 3 (Box 17)
      - Zurich., 2 (Box 17)
    - Gutierrez, Juan Simon, 1644-1718., 4 (Box 17)
- H (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Artists H., 3 (Box 17)
    - Hamen y Leon, Jan van der, 1596-1632., 3 (Box 17)
  - Individual Artists H., 12 (Box 17)
    - Herrera le Vieux, 1576-1656., 1 (Box 17)
    - Herrera, Francisco de the Younger, 1622-1685., 3 (Box 17)
    - Huguet, Jaume, c.1415-1494., 8 (Box 17)
- J (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Artists J., 6 (Box 17)
    - Jativa Master, XVI C., 1 (Box 17)
    - Jimeno y Planes, Rafael, 1761-1825., 1 (Box 17)
    - Jiminez, Louis, active 1845., 1 (Box 17)
    - Juan de Burgos, active 1425-1450., 1 (Box 17)
    - Juan de Sevilla, 1643-1695., 1 (Box 17)
    - Junyer, Joan, 1904-., 1 (Box 17)
  - Individual Artists J., 45 (Box 17)
    - Juan de Flandes, active c.1496-1519., 23 (Box 17)
    - Juan de Juanes, 1500-1579., 22 (Box 18)
- L (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Artists L., 4 (Box 18)
    - El Labrador, active 1630's., 1 (Box 18)
    - Lago, Antonio, XX C., 1 (Box 18)
    - Ledesma, Blas de, XVI C., 1 (Box 18)
    - Leon y Escosura, 1840-1901., 1 (Box 18)
  - Individual Artists L., 13 (Box 18)
    - Leonardo, Jusepe, 1616-1656., 1 (Box 18)
    - Lopez, Vicente, 1772-1850., 2 (Box 18)
    - Lucas y Padilla, Eugenio, 1824-1870., 4 (Box 18)
    - Lucas de Villamil, Eugenio, 1824-1870., 6 (Box 18)
- M (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Artists M., 4 (Box 18)
    - Master of Guimera, XV C., 1 (Box 18)
    - Mateos, Francisco, 1896-., 1 (Box 18)
    - Minguillon, Julia, XX C., 1 (Box 18)
    - Moragas, T., XIX C., 1 (Box 18)
  - Individual Artists M., 509 (Box 18)
    - Machuca, Pedro, active 1516-1550., 2 (Box 18)
    - Madrazo, Raimundo, 1841-1920., 8 (Box 18)
      Also called Ricardo Madrazo y Garreta.
    - Maestro Alfonso, active 1473., 4 (Box 18)
    - Marquez de Velasco, Esteban, -1720., 27 (Box 18)
    - Martorell, Bernardo, -1453., 12 (Box 19)
      Also known as the Master of St. George.
    - Master of the Retable of the Catholic Kings, XV C., 13 (Box 19)
    - Master of the Solsena Last Supper, XV C., 5 (Box 19)
    - Master of Sijena, active 1519., 1 (Box 19)
    - Mayno, Juan Bautista, 1568-1649., 5 (Box 19)
    - Mazo, Juan Bautista del, 1612-1667., 19 (Box 19)
    - Melendez, Luis Egidio, 1716-1780., 15 (Box 19)
    - Meneses Osorio, Francisco, active 1666-1680., 5 (Box 19)
    - Miro, Joan, 1893-1983., 123 (Box 20)
      - Undated works and works before 1920., 24 (Box 20)
      - Works from the 1920's., 36 (Box 20)
      - Works from the 1930's., 23 (Box 20)
      - Works from the 1940's., 21 (Box 20)
      - Works from the 1950's., 9 (Box 21)
      - Works from the 1960's and later., 10 (Box 21)
    - Morales, Luis de, 1509-1586., 14 (Box 21)
    - Murillo, Bartolome Esteban, 1618-1682., 254 (Box 21)
      - Drawings., 3 (Box 21)
      - Paintings., 251 (Box 21)
        - Locations not noted., 21 (Box 21)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 22 (Box 21)
        - Birmingham., 3 (Box 22)
        - Cleveland., 7 (Box 22)
        - Detroit., 6 (Box 22)
        - Dresden., 5 (Box 22)
        - Florence., 6 (Box 22)
        - Leningrad., 6 (Box 22)
        - London., 25 (Box 22)
        - Madrid., 15 (Box 22)
        - Madrid., 15 (Box 23)
        - Munich., 51 (Box 23)
        - New York., 4 (Box 23)
        - Ottawa., 3 (Box 23)
        - Paris., 10 (Box 23)
        - Raleigh., 5 (Box 23)
        - Rome., 7 (Box 24)
        - Seville., 36 (Box 24)
        - Washington, D.C., 9 (Box 24)
- N (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Artists N., 3 (Box 24)
    - Nonell y Monturiol, Isidro, 1873-1911., 3 (Box 24)
  - Individual Artists N., 10 (Box 24)
    - Nestor Fernandez de la Torre, 1869-., 2 (Box 24)
    - Nunez de Villavicencio, Pedro, 1644-1700., 8 (Box 24)
- O (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Artists O., 1 (Box 24)
    - Oller, Francisco, 1833-1917., 1 (Box 24)
  - Individual Artists O., 3 (Box 24)
    - Ortoneda, Mateo, -1417., 3 (Box 24)
- P (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Artists P., 9 (Box 24)
    - Palanquinos Master, c.1500., 1 (Box 24)
    - Palencia, Benjamin, XX C., 1 (Box 24)
    - Palomino de Castro y Velasco, A.A., 1653-1726., 1 (Box 24)
    - Paret y Alcazar, Luis, 1746-1799., 1 (Box 24)
    - Perez, Bartolome, 1634-1693., 1 (Box 24)
    - Pomar, Julio, 1926-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Ponc, Joan, 1927-1984., 2 (Box 24)
    - Puga, Antonio, active 1650-1660., 1 (Box 24)
  - Individual Artists P., 523 (Box 25)
    - Palmaroli y Gonzales, Vincente, 1834/5-1896., 4 (Box 25)
    - Pantoja de la Cruz, Juan, 1553-1608., 12 (Box 25)
    - Pereda, Antonio, 1608-1678., 4 (Box 25)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1881--1973., 501 (Box 25)
      - Miscellany, including photos of the artist., 3 (Box 25)
      - Drawings., 32 (Box 25)
      - Paintings., 466 (Box 25)
        - Undated works., 18 (Box 25)
        - Undated works., 18 (Box 26)
        - Works from the late 19th C., 2 (Box 26)
        - Works from 1900-1902., 39 (Box 26)
        - Works from 1903-1904., 23 (Box 26)
        - Works from 1905-1906., 22 (Box 26)
        - Works from 1905-1906., 22 (Box 27)
        - Works from 1907-1908., 30 (Box 27)
        - Works from 1909-1910., 24 (Box 27)
        - Works from 1911-1914., 35 (Box 28)
        - Works from 1915-1920., 24 (Box 28)
        - Works from 1921-1923., 38 (Box 28)
        - Works from 1924-1929., 20 (Box 29)
        - Works from 1930-1934., 29 (Box 29)
        - Works from 1935-1939., 40 (Box 29)
        - Works from 1940-1945., 31 (Box 30)
        - Works from 1946-1959., 32 (Box 30)
        - Works from after 1960., 19 (Box 30)
    - Pruna, Pedro, 1904-., 2 (Box 30)
- Q (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Artists Q., 2 (Box 30)
    - Quintanilla, Luis, 1893-1978., 1 (Box 30)
    - Quiros, Cesareo Bernaldo, 1881-., 1 (Box 30)
- R (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Artists R., 3 (Box 30)
    - Ribera, Roman, 1848-., 1 (Box 30)
    - Rincon, Fernando del, active 1491-1518., 1 (Box 30)
    - Ruiz de la Iglesia, Francisco, 1648-1704., 1 (Box 30)
  - Individual Artists R., 193 (Box 31)
    - Ribalta, Francisco de, 1551-1628., 25 (Box 31)
    - Ribera, Jusepe de, 1588-1652., 159 (Box 31)
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 31)
      - Paintings., 153 (Box 31)
        - Locations not noted., 14 (Box 31)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 29 (Box 31)
        - Cleveland., 3 (Box 31)
        - Dresden., 8 (Box 31)
        - Florence., 4 (Box 31)
        - Hartford., 3 (Box 32)
        - London., 4 (Box 32)
        - Madrid., 23 (Box 32)
        - Munich., 15 (Box 32)
        - Naples., 20 (Box 32)
        - New York., 4 (Box 32)
        - Paris., 9 (Box 32)
        - Rome., 17 (Box 33)
    - Rico y Ortega, Martin, 1833-1908., 2 (Box 33)
    - Rizi, Francisco, 1608-1685., 2 (Box 33)
    - Rizi, Juan, 1595-1675., 5 (Box 33)
- S (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous Artists S, 7 (Box 33)
    - Sala, Raphael, 1895-., 1 (Box 33)
    - Sanchez-Perrier, Emilio, 1855-1907., 2 (Box 33)
    - Simonet y Lombardo, XIX C., 1 (Box 33)
    - Solana, Jose Gutierrez, 1886-1945., 1 (Box 33)
    - Soria, Martin de, XV C., 1 (Box 33)
    - Sunyer, Joaquin, 1875-1957., 1 (Box 33)
  - Individual Artists S., 45 (Box 33)
    - Sanchez-Cotan, Juan, 1561-1627., 3 (Box 33)
    - Serra, Jaume, active 1360-1375., 3 (Box 33)
    - Sert, Jose Maria, 1876-1945., 15 (Box 33)
    - Sorolla y Bastida, Joaquin, 1863-1923., 24 (Box 33)
- T (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous Artists T., 5 (Box 33)
    - Togores, Jose de, XX C., 1 (Box 33)
    - Torres-Garcia, Joaquin, 1895-1949., 4 (Box 33)
  - Individual Artists T, 37 (Box 34)
    - Tapies, Antoni, 1923-., 19 (Box 34)
    - Torres, Clemente de, 1662-1730., 4 (Box 34)
    - Tovar, Alonso Miguel de, 1678-1758., 14 (Box 34)
- V (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous Artists V., 10 (Box 34)
    - Valencia, Pedro de, XX C., 1 (Box 34)
    - Vargas, Francisco de, active c.1621., 1 (Box 34)
    - Vargas, Luis de, 1502-1568., 3 (Box 34)
    - Vazquez, Alonzo, active 1600-1637., 1 (Box 34)
    - Vicente, Esteban, 1906-., 2 (Box 34)
    - Victoria, Vicente, 1650-1713., 1 (Box 34)
    - Villandrando, Rodrigo de, -1628., 1 (Box 34)
  - Individual Artists V., 327 (Box 34)
    - Valdes-Leal, Juan de, 1630-1690., 21 (Box 34)
    - Velasquez, Diego, 1599-1660., 304 (Box 34)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 34)
      - Paintings., 300 (Box 35)
        - Locations not noted and miscellaneous cities., 26 (Box 35)
        - Berlin., 7 (Box 35)
        - Boston., 6 (Box 35)
        - Chicago., 3 (Box 35)
        - Florence., 4 (Box 35)
        - Leningrad., 5 (Box 35)
        - London., 23 (Box 35)
        - London., 22 (Box 36)
        - Madrid., 132 (Box 36)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 19 (Box 36)
          - Las Meninas., 13 (Box 36)
          - Surrender of Breda., 8 (Box 36)
          - Saragossa., 6 (Box 36)
          - Portraits of men., 26 (Box 36)
          - Portraits of men., 26 (Box 37)
          - Portraits of women., 20 (Box 37)
          - Religious themes., 14 (Box 37)
        - Modena., 2 (Box 37)
        - Munich., 8 (Box 37)
        - Naples., 2 (Box 37)
        - New York., 10 (Box 37)
        - New York., 9 (Box 38)
        - Paris., 8 (Box 38)
        - Rome., 3 (Box 38)
        - Sao Paolo., 4 (Box 38)
        - Vienna., 18 (Box 38)
        - Washington, D.C., 6 (Box 38)
    - Vergos, J.P. y Rafael, -1495., 2 (Box 38)
- Y, Z (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous Artists Y, Z., 5 (Box 38)
    - Yanez, Fernando, active1504-1531., 2 (Box 38)
    - Zadkine, Ossip, 1890-1967., 1 (Box 38)
    - Zamacois, Edward, 1842-1871., 1 (Box 38)
    - Zush, 1946-., 1 (Box 38)
  - Individual Artists Y, Z., 122 (Box 38)
    - Zuloaga, Ignacio, 1870-1945., 12 (Box 38)
    - Zuloaga, Ignacio, 1870-1945., 12 (Box 39)
    - Zurbaran, Francisco de, 1598-1662., 98 (Box 39)
      - Locations not noted., 8 (Box 39)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 64 (Box 39)
      - Madrid., 11 (Box 39)
      - Seville., 15 (Box 39)